Guide to Peter P. Carr Papers RG.055
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series I: American Options, 1965-2002; 60 Linear Feet
  - The Valuation of American Put Options with Exponential Exercise Policies; Omberg, Edward; Adv's in Fut And Options Res., 1987; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Arbitraging Options: The Case of the Live Real Option and Dead Synthetic Option; Omberg, 1989-01; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Option Pricing: The American Put; Parkinson, Michael JB, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Monte Carlo Valuation of American Options; Rogers, L.C.G.; UBath, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Rational Theory of Warrant Pricing Appendix: A Free Boundary Problem for the Heat Equation Arising from a Problem in Mathematical Economics; Samuelson/McKean; Industrial Mgmt. Rev., 1965; 60 Linear Feet (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Verification of American Put; Reddy, 1990-08-2000-06; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Optimal Stopping and American Put Options; Salminen, Paavo; Th. of Stochastic Processes, 1995; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - A Reduction Method Applicable to Compound Option Formulas; Schroder, Mark, MS, 1989; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Computing Parity Results for American Options Using a Change of Measure; Schroder, M.; SUNY Buffalo WP, 1996-05; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "The Valuation of American Options in Stochastic Interest Rate Economies"; Stapleton/Subrahmanyam, 1991-08; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Optimal Investments Using Empirical Dynamic Programming with Application to Natural Resources; Stensland and Tjostheim, 1989-01; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Assessing the Least Squares Monte-Carlo Approach to American Option Valuation; Stentoft, L., 2001-08; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Convergence of the Least Squares Monte-Carlo Approach to American Option Valuation; Stentoft, L., 2002-06; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pricing American Options when the Underlying Stock Price Exhibits Time-Varying Volatility; Stentoft, Lars, 2002-06; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Su, Yi: Univ. of Maryland at Risk Conferences; "Pricing American Options via Simulation: A Comparison of Monte Carlo Simulation Approaches", Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Subrahmanyam, M.G. & Yu, G.G.; Pricing and Hedging American Options: A Unified Method and its Efficient Implementation; Working paper, 1993-09 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Taylor, Howard; Management Science, September '67; Evaluating a Call Option and Optimal Timing Strategy in the Stock Market, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Tilley, J.; Morgan Stanley WP; Valuing American Options in a Path Simulation Model, 1992-05-15 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Tsitsiklis & Van Roy; Optimal Stopping of Markov Processes: Hilbert Space Theory, Approximation Algorithms, & an Application to Pricing High-Dimensional Financial Derivatives, 1998-10 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Tsitsiklis & Van Roy; Regression Methods for Pricing Complex American-Style Options, 2000-08 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Touzi, N.; Appl Math Optim '99; American Options Exercise Boundary When the Volatility Changes Randomly, Undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Van Moerbeke, Pierre; On Optimal Stopping and Free Boundary Problems, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Villeneuve, Stephane; Exercise Regions of American Options on several assets, 1997-06 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Viswanathan, Ravi; American Option's Bounds: Tanaka's Formula and Snell Envelopes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Wei, Jason Z.; Valuing American Equity Options with a Stochastic Interest Rate: A Note, Undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Wu, L., Kwok, Y., Zhu, Y.; Fixed-Domain Finite Difference Methods for American Options, Undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Wu & Kwok; A Front-Fixing Finite Difference Method for the Valuation of American Options, Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Yaksick, R.; Expected Optimal Exercise Time of a Perpetual American Option: A Closed-form Solution, Undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Yang & Yuan; Another New Way to Price American Options by Using the Interior Point Method, 1999-08-05 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Yu, Gang; Valuation of American Options in Stochastic Interest Rate Economics, 1992-03 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Yu, Gang George; Essays on the Valuation of American Options, 1993-04 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Yu, Gang; Valuation of American Options: A Simplified Approach and Applications, 1992-12 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - A Simplified Approach to the Valuation of American Options and Applications, Undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Yu, Kwok & Wu; Valuation of American lookback Options, 1997-10 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Zhang, Xiao; Numerical Analysis of American Option Pricing in a Jump-Diffusion Model, Undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Bates, David; The Crash of '87; Relative Prices of OTM Calls & Puts under Standard Distributional Hypotheses, Undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - T. Gayley; A Mathlink Program for Accessing Binary Files; Mathematica Journal, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - A. Conze; European Path Dependent Options: The Case of Geometric Averages, 1989-09 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - M. Curran; Valuing Asian and Portfolio Options by Conditioning on the Geometric Mean Price, 1993-05 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - D. Grant, G. Vora & D. Weeks; Path-dependent Options: Extending the Monte Carlo Simulation Approach, 1993-11 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - J. M. Haykov; A Better Control Variate for Pricing Standard Asian Options; J. Fin. Eng. 2, 207-216, 1993-09 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - J. Hull; Interest Rate Exotics; Risk Exotic Options Conference, 1994-04 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - F. Jamshidian; Hedging Quantos, Diff Swaps and Ratios, 1993-05 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - E. Reiner; Quanto Mechanics; Risk, Undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - M. Rubenstein; Two Into One; Risk 4, #5, 1991-05 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - M. York; On Some Exponential Functionals of Browian Motion; Adv. Appl. Prob. 24, 509-531, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Bumping Up Against the Barrier with the Binomial Method; P.P. Boyle & S.H. Lau, 1994; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - An Introduction to Special-purpose Derivatives: Roll Up Puts, Roll Down...J. Derivatives; G.L. Gastineau, 1994; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Back to Baskets; C.B. Huynh, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Contingent Premium Options; H.M. Kat, 1994; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Binomial Valuation of Lookback Options; S.H. Babbs, 1992-04; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - On Inferring Standard Deviations from Path Dependent Options, Econ. Ltrs. 18; C.A. Ball, W.N. Torous & A.E. Tschoegl, 1985-01-15; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Down and Out, Up and In Options; D. Beaglehole, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Up, Over and Out, Risk 4 No. 6; R. Benson & N. Daniel, 1991-06; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Pricing Path Contingent Claims, Res. In Finance, 5; Y.Z. Bergman, 1985; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - The Value in Going Out, Risk; M. Hudson, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Hedging and Evaluating Diff Swaps; F. Jamshidian, 1993-04; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Valuation of Average-dependent Options; Reiner, Undated; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - The Mathematical Foundations of Barrier Option Pricing Theory, Adv. Futures & Options Res., Forthcoming; D.R. Rich, 1994-01; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - An Alternative Approach to the Pricing of Options on Multiple Assets, J. Fin. Eng. 2; D.R. Rich & D.M. Chance, 1993; 60 Linear Feet (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - M. Rubinstein & E. Reiner, Breaking Down the Barriers; Risk 4, No. 8, 1991-09 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - J. Wei, Streams of Consequence; Risk 7, #1, 1994-01 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - J.Z. Wei, Valuing Differential Swaps, 1993-01-08 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - K.I. Amin, Jump Diffusion Option Valuation in Discrete Time; J. Finance Vol. XLVIII, #5, 1993-12 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - G. Barone-Adesi & R.E. Whaley, Efficient Analytic Approximation of American Option Values; J. Finance Vol. XLII, 1987-06 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - R. Breen, The Accelerated Binomial Option Pricing Model; J. Fin. & Quant. Analy 26, #2, 1991-06 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - A. Carverhill & N. Webber, American Options: Theory and Numerical Analysis, 1988-07 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - M. Chesney, Pricing American Currency Options: An Analytical Approach; Centre HEC ISA, France, Undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - N.J. Cutland & E. Kopp, From Discrete to Continuous Financial Models: New Convergence Results for Option Pricing; Math. Fin. 3, #2, 101-123, 1993-04 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - R. Geske & H.E. Johnson, The American Put Option Valued Analytically; J. Fin. Vol. XXXIX, #5, 1984-12 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - L.W. MacMillan, Analytic Approximation for the American Put Option; Adv. Fut. & Options Res. Vol. 1, Part A, 119-139, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - R.C. Merton, M.J. Brennan & E.S. Schwartz, The Valuation of American Put Options; J. Fin. Vol. XXXII, #2, 1977-05 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - E. Omberg, The Valuation of American Put Options with Exponential Exercise Policies; Adv. Fut. & Options Res. Vol 2: 117-142, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - M.G. Subrahmanyam & G.G. Yu, Pricing and Hedging American Options: A Unified Method and its Efficient Implementation, 1993-09 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - The Economics of the Reflection Principle and Girsanov's Theorem, Undated (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - EPCS - European Put Call Symmetry, 1993-12-1994-05 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Even Functions, Undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - APCS Resubmit, 1996-11-1997-06 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Letter from Bjerksund & Stensland, 1998-11-04 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Olsen & Stensland, Invariant Controls in Stochastic Allocation Problems, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Bjerksund & Stensland, American Exchange Options and a Put-Call Transformation: A Note; JBFA, 1993-09 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Bjerksund & Stensland, Closed-form Approximation of American Options; Scand. J. Mgmt, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Continuous Random Variable and Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - AMEX Letter, 1993-09-22-1993-12-16 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - American Put Call Symmetry, Undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Margrabe's Web Site, 1999-08-03 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - APC Pres, Undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - APCS in Same Economy, Undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Barrier Option Typeups, Undated (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Chesney Rewrite, Undated (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Green's Function & PCS, Undated (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Hedging ITM UIC's with using PCS UIP's, Undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - FX Options, Undated (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Installment Options, 1993-08-1993-10 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Installment Stoptions (on Spot), Undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Installment Options, 1993-08-03 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - (Installment) (St)options on Forward, Undated (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Journal Submission, 1995-07-26-1997-05-13 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Linear Homogeneity, Undated (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Lookbacks, Undated (Box 3, Folder 95)
- Series II: APCS and AMOL, 0
  - Manuscript, 1993-06-1996-11-13 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Passthru Options, Undated (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Perpetual Options Counterexample, Undated (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Physical Interpretation of Put Call Symmetry, Undated (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Portfolio Ins/Zero Cost Collars, Undated (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Put Call Equivalence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - PCEE, 1994-05-20-1995-12-13 (Box 3, Folder 102)